

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

■ me@joshoberhaus.com | 😭 www.joshoberhaus.com | 🖸 joshOberhaus | 🛅 joshoberhaus

With 8 years specializing in Driver Assistance, I bring expertise in Radar-based tracking and fusion, alongside a diverse skill set from a total of 14 years in the automotive industry. Committed to ongoing learning and empowering colleagues: I've revamped visualization tools, introduced two generations of tracking KPI tools, and conducted various training sessions on perception and fusion all to make working on tracking more accessible and enjoyable.

I'm a strong team player which I've demonstrated through leading critical customer meetings and stepping into the role of Product Owner as needed.

Experience

Robert Bosch LLC Hybrid | Plymouth, MI

TECHNICAL EXPERT - PERCEPTION | TRACKING

Jan. 2024 - Present

Sep. 2018 - Jan. 2024

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - PERCEPTION | TRACKING

- Served as a technical lead for a global platform perception / fusion software team.
- Secured a strategic acquistion through realizing tracking gains brought by architectural changes for a 5 radar 1 video configuration.
- Optimized radar-based perception for a new generation of radar sensor.
- Developed several new features for MATLAB-based tracking visualization tooling, including projection of the components of the Kalman filter, and automation abilities.
- · Developed Python-based KPI Tool for single target tracking analysis, integrated and automated its execution as a Jenkins pipeline.
- Increased performance of corner radar-based tracking (C++) by identifying and addressing assumptions made towards front-facing radars.
- · Reworked object type classification feature calculations to be more agnostic of sensor-mounting, reducing missed-target scenarios.

Bosch Engineering North America

Farmington Hills, MI Apr. 2016 - Sep. 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - PREDICTIVE SAFETY SYSTEMS

- Served as the Predictive Safety System (AEB, FCW, System Conditioning) component responsible for a strategic customer.
- Developed Python-based data mining tools to open new opportunities in evaluating data sets from endurance runs.
- · Introduced automated tooling to enable customer-friendly overviews for endurance run points of interest.
- · Led labelling sessions with the customer, explaining and addressing concerns with any activations.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Apr. 2012 - Apr. 2016

- Developed unique solution for criticality classification for marine radar collision warning applications, modified tracking and localization logic to be less dependent on traffic-scenes.
- Designed and implemented Python-based code generation tool chain to allow a Bosch-created library to be integrated into a third-party controller.
- Supported customers on site in solving critical plant issues.
- Created an ABS simulation software (C-based) and testing client (in CANAPE/CAPL) for OEM brake component testing, greatly reducing the OEM
 endurance run effort.
- · Served as diagnostic component responsible and integrator in Electronic Power Steering (EPS) and EBCM projects.
- · Integrated ASIL-D control functions in EPS unit, to facilitate level three functions, the first for that product generation.
- Network and diagnostic communication component responsible for multiple EPS and EBCM projects; configured, implemented, and tested several CAN and diagnostic stacks (J1939, UDS) in C.
- · Led global diagnostic communication software development team, coordinating tasks and workload.

Skills

Programming C++, Python, MATLAB, C, Julia

Middleware Automotive Operating System (AOS), ROS

Education

Kettering University Flint, MI

B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, SUMMA CUM LAUDE

2008-2012